

Senior Analyst seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Java Script, Bootstrap, SQL Server, jQuery, JIRA, HTML, CSS



Current Designation: Application Development Senior Analyst Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Analyst, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SQL Server, iQuery, JIRA, HTML, CSS

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

## Summary

A Software Engineer having overall 5.11 years of extensive experience Software Development of enterprise level web application using Microsoft Technologies. Have hands on experience on C#, Asp.Net MVC, Web API, SQL Server, Angular(v5,7,9,10), HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Firebase, Azure.

And also have knowledge on different domain like Insurance, Learning, HR, Media & Entertainment.

To secure a challenging position in an organization to utilize my technical and analytical skills as well as to enhance my knowledge about new and emerging trends and technologies.

# Work Experience

Accenture as Application Development Senior Analyst Sep 2018 to Till Date

Project 1: Learning Vendor Catalog (Duration 7 month)

Domain: Learning

Role & Responsibility: Attended scrum call. Solved vulnerability / security issue in the

application. Upgrading the angular application. Setting the

DevOps pipeline.

Project 2: Falcon (Duration 1.6 years)

Domain: Learning

Role & Responsibility: Attended daily scrum call. Created API and Angular Component.

Created and modified existing SP. Did Unit Testing for Angular application. Weekly demo presentation for the responsible task.

# Prime Focus Technologies as Senior Software Engineer

May 2018 to Sep 2018

Project 1: Lions Gate ( Duration 4 months)

Domain: Media & Entertainment

Role & Responsibility: Gathered client requirement. Configured the product

according to client need. Created tool for error finding and rectification.

### Mphasis Pvt. Ltd as Delivery Software Engineer

Jan 2015 to May 2018

Project 1: TalentViewer (Duration 2 years)

Domain: HR

Role & Responsibility: Handled daily client call. Created high level design document.

Gathered client requirement. Writing Store Procedures, API

and also creating UI, etc.

Project 2: Valic Re-design(Duration 1.3 years)

Domain: Insurance

Role & Responsibility: Created Models for the module, Writing Code for Data access,

Business layer, did UI integration. Created the design document.

#### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from THIRD EYE COLLEGE in 2011

PG: MCA (Computers) from Reva institute of technology and management in 2014

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

AZ-900

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C#, Oops Concept , Tsql.			
ASP.NET, ADO.NET , jQuery , CSS ,HTML			
LINQ,java script, xml			
MVC. Framework .NET Framework 4.0			
MS Visual Studio (2017,2015,2013, 2012 &			
SQLServer2008,2014			
Team Foundation Server, IIS 7.0			
Angular	9	2020	1 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
Microsoft Azure	AZ 203		
GIT		2020	1 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Bengali	Proficient			
Assamese	Proficient			

## **Projects**

Project Title: Falcon Client: Accenture

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2018 - Nov 2019

Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 14

Skill Used: ASP.Net MVC, Angular 7, SQL Server, C#, Html5

Role Description: Creating and Modify Angular component, Store Procedure and Dot net project.

Project Details: Falcon is a redesign project of learning domain. Its a portal where employees can do online virtual courses and also scheduled class room training. In this portal we also have third party integration due to which we can see the vendor courses as well.

Project Title: LGMovies Client: LionsGate

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2018 - Jul 2018 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: c#. SQL server, asp.net . MVC, azure storage

Role Description: Creating tools for finding the mismatch and error in the existing essences and built a tool to autocorrect the

Done existing database migration. Creat dashboard for the client.

Project Details: This project helps our client Lionsgate's to maintain and manage their media asset like creating promo,

thumbnail, publishing the promo in different social media etc.

Project Title: RUBIK Automation

Client: Mphasis

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2016 - Till Date Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Sal Server. C#. MVC

Role Description: Designing documents, requirement gathering, and requirement analysis, coding and testing. Created High

level design documents.

Worked on layered architecture. Used TFS for version control. Tested the whole application. Regular Status. Work on AGILE. Project Details: RUBIK is automation tool which help the Talent Fulfilment Group (TFG) to fill the workforce requirement of the project. This tool is helpful for the organization employee as well to track their project allocation status.

And also this RUBIK tool also help the management to track their bench, client opening close status. Which help them in

their costing calculation

Project Title: VALIC Online Re Design

Client: AIG

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2015 - Aug 2016 Project Location: Chennai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 20

Skill Used: ORACLE, C#, ASP.Net MVC,

Role Description: Designing documents, requirement gathering, and requirement analysis, coding and testing. Created High level design documents. Worked on layered architecture. Done coding for each layer.

Used TFS for version control. Worked on AGILE methodology.

Project Details: VALIC Digital is an Alacarte project with the core of digitalization that includes the latest features such as AEM for content management and the MVC as the design framework that opens a new digital world for the existing project. It is a highly valued for customer transaction site with lot of core features to manage their current and future plans that includes the retirement schemes. The application is designed in such a way with the current market standard where it is now made available for the users at their finger points by making it available in Mobile, tablet and so on with responsive design. On the whole it gives the user a better new look experience with core competencies.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time